Hello everyone and welcome to English mod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're
talking about the human body, right Marco?
That's right today we are going to take
a look at very specific vocabulary words
related to your body, what's inside your
body. So let's just jump right into this
dialogue.
Let's listen to this anatomy class.
Okay class, so today we're going to
continue with our anatomy class. Today we
will review everything we have learned.
Can anyone tell me what the first major
organ is? The brain. That's right the
brain. It serves as a control center for
the body handling the processes of the
central nervous system as well as cognition.
Then what major organ is in
our chest? The heart. Very good.
It pumps blood throughout
the body using the
circulatory system such
as blood vessels and veins.
Now let's not forget that our lungs
provide oxygen to our heart and
body to keep us alive. Now what
about the organs that help us digest food?
The stomach and intestines. Very good.
Let's not forget that the stomach is the
one that breaks down our food and
our intestines process the food and then
expel the waste. Are
we forgetting anything?
Yeah our kidneys,
liver and bladder.
Oh yes you are right. Very important
organs indeed. So what do these organs do
to teach her? Well, they time for a break.
We can talk about it when you get back.
All right we're back so now let's take
a look at some vocab on language take
away. Language take away. So the first
word we have today is anatomy. We've heard
this already. This is the study of the
body right? That's right so maybe in high
school you took an anatomy class you
studied the bodies maybe of animals for
example. That's right but if we're talking
about human beings we would call it
human anatomy and we would study the
things like your organs, your bones, all
the things that make up your body.
That's right and that's our next word we're
talking about our body organs. Now
this is important where are these located
Marco inside or outside? Inside. Inside
the body. So the body has many different
organs and we learned all about
these in today's dialogue but an organ is
basically a part. A part of your body. It
has a special function or many functions.
Yeah that's right so for example we talked
about the heart. We all know what the
heart is and it's one of our main organs
with that pumps blood through our body.
That's right and so some of these
organs have to do with processing food.
Some have to do with blood but there's
also an interesting system that we heard
about called the central nervous system.
That's right and this is very closely
related to the brain and so basically
the nervous system is in charge of all
the things that you feel in your body.
That's right so you feel through what
are called nerves and the central
the central nervous system is actually a
system that connects all these things
together and then connects it to the brain.
So think of a system as being comprised
of many different parts not just one nerve.
That's right so we're talking
about for example your skin is part
of the nervous system your eyes what
you see and all this gets fed into the
brain and it process it and that's
what the basically the nervous system is
all about. That's right and the brain
is also important for other things.
We heard about this noun cognition. Yeah
the doctor said yeah the teacher said that
cognition was one of the other things
that the brain helped us with. So what
exactly is cognition? Cognition is the
ability to think all right so humans have
cognition that means we have brains
and our brains allow us to think and even
talk and write music and things like
that but for example a rock does not have
cognition. A plant would not have
cognition either because they don't have
this special organ the brain that allows
them to think. Right so it's a noun right?
You say that we have cognition because
we have brains. That's right you have it.
Okay so those are the four words
that we're going to take a look at to
introduce the lesson. Why don't we
move on now to more specific vocab let's
take a look at some of the main organs
that we discussed in this dialogue on
language takeaway part two.
Okay class so today we're going to
continue with our anatomy class. Today we
will review everything we have learned.
Can anyone tell me what the first major
organ is? The brain. That's right the
brain. It serves as a control center for
the body handling the processes of the
central nervous system as well as cognition.
Then what major organ is in
our chest? The heart. Very good.
It pumps blood throughout
the body using the
circulatory system such
as blood vessels and veins.
Now let's not forget that our lungs
provide oxygen to our heart and
body to keep us alive. Now what about
the organs that help us digest food? The
stomach and intestines. Very good let's
not forget that the stomach is the one
that breaks down our food and our
intestines process the food and then
expel the waste. Are
we forgetting anything?
Yeah our kidneys
liver and bladder. Oh
yes you are right very important organs
indeed. So what did these organs do
to teach her? Well um they time for a
break we can talk about it when you get
back. So we're moving down the body we
had the brain and we mentioned the stomach.
We had the brain and then the heart of
course which pumps blood like you say
Marco but the next item the next organ
is the stomach. That's right so we get to
the stomach and the intestines which are
very closely bound together so what does
this stomach do first? First of all when
you eat food the food is sent to your
stomach where your stomach breaks it
down and decides what parts to keep and
what parts to to say right. Right
and the interesting thing is that in our
stomachs we have what we call acid.
Yeah so these acids break down those
foods because it all gets mixed
together in there and your body has to
determine what exactly you've been eating.
Right exactly so after the stomach
breaks things down it goes through
the intestines and also the intestines are
very important and they're very long but
they're all wound up inside our stomach.
That's right they they kind of
look like a lot of s's because they're
all coiled up inside of us and they are
indeed quite long but the intestines are
also very very important because
they're actually what the waste or the
parts of food that our bodies don't
need so they travel through to get out of
our systems. That's right. So actually
the intestines will absorb part of the
proteins and the vitamins and everything
that we need and at the same time they
will also act as little tunnels that will
transport the waste that things that
we don't need to have inside our body
to later be able to digest. That's right
so the stomach and the intestines
those have to do with the way that we eat
process and dispose of food but now
we have the kidneys. Okay so people have
two kidneys right. Yeah that's right
people have two kidneys and actually you
can continue living with with just one
kidney right. That's right they're kind
of shapes like a sea almost. In fact we
have something called a kidney bean in
English which is a red bean and it looks
just like a kidney. Okay and well what
do the kidneys do? The kidneys from what
I understand basically clean your blood.
So you know there's lots of things
in your in your system in your body
especially from the things that you
eat and maybe the chemicals that you're
exposed to and we need our kidneys.
At least the one kidney to clean our blood
and make sure our blood is is what
it's supposed to be. And in fact when the
kidneys aren't working properly
it's very very serious and we call this
kidney failure. Right so when you're
watching a TV show about doctors maybe you
say oh he's gone into kidney failure.
Right. It's a big deal. Very big problem.
Alright so this is what our kidneys do. A
very important part of our bodies obviously
and well as you said they act as filters
but near the kidneys we also have the
liver. That's right. Liver is actually for
some people a delicious food not human
liver but animal liver. But in humans
we also have this organ right and it's
also closely related to people who have
drinking problems. They have bad livers.
Uh-huh and why is that? I think it
has to do a little bit with what the the
liver does. It does many different
things but alcohol I think harms your
liver makes it weaker and the liver is
important because it helps to generate
hormones but it also helps us
process chemicals in our body. Right.
Yeah so this is really important actually
the why the liver is so important is
because it does so much and well we only
got one of them so we can't really live
without it right. That's right so the
liver is a very important thing and
actually many people now have gone
through liver transplants. That means that
their liver stops working so they
receive the liver of another person. Right.
Yeah so you might hear that as well on TV.
And the last organ that we took a
look at here is the bladder which is also
very important goes hand-in-hand with
the kidneys. It does it does so the
bladder you might hear someone say I have a
bad bladder that means that I
often have to use the bathroom. Right.
So urinate. Mm-hmm. Now the bladder
is where liquids and also some kinds of
chemicals in our bodies that we get
from the food that we eat are kept until
we dispose of them. Right. Right exactly.
All right so so actually when your
bladder is full because it gets full of
liquid or urine that's when you have to
go to the bathroom. That's right and so
pregnant women often have weak weaker
bladders they they feel pressure on
the bladder so it hurts and that doesn't
hurt it pushes down the bladder the baby
does so they often have to pee very often.
Unlike people who are not pregnant.
Okay very very interesting and
actually the some people say that you
know I have a small bladder and that's
why they go to the bathroom all the
time more often than others. Now why don't
we take a look at our
dialogue for the last time and
we'll be back in a bit
to talk a little bit more.
Okay class so today we're going to
continue with our anatomy class. Today we
will review everything we have learned.
Can anyone tell me what the first major
organ is? The brain.
That's right the brain.
It serves as a
control center for the
body handling the processes of the central
nervous system as well as cognition.
Then what major organ is in our
chest? The heart. Very good. It pumps
blood throughout the body using the
circulatory system such as blood vessels
and veins. Now let's not forget that
our lungs provide oxygen to our heart and
body to keep us alive. Now what
about the organs that help us digest food?
The stomach and intestines. Very good.
Let's not forget that the stomach is the one
that breaks down our food and our
intestines process the food and then
expel the waste. Are we forgetting anything?
Yeah our kidneys, liver and bladder.
Oh yes you are right. Very important
organs indeed. So what do these
organs do to teach her? Well um they
time for a break we can talk about it when
you get back. All right so you
mentioned that actually some people get
liver transplants so out of all these
organs we could also have a kidney
transplant right? You can donate your
kidneys. You can you can so obviously you
can't have any kidney you actually have
to have a match. You know someone who is
the right type but oftentimes they do
perform these surgeries with the kidney
transplant or a liver transplant.
Now what about a heart transplant?
I believe they've done tests of heart
transplants and they've done a few successful
ones. Sometimes they use pieces of
cow or pig hearts because they have very
similar genetic make-ups to human
beings so they can use little pieces like
valves but I really don't know I don't
think they're as common as as liver or
kidney. That's right and actually these
organs they're you know we don't really
pay too much attention to them but
they're so very delicate and they do so
many things that that actually once
you only begin having some problems with
them that's when you realize how
important they are. That's right so it's
really important to understand a little
bit about how they work and also how to
take care of them because obviously
if you're having liver problems you
should stop drinking so much that you
know there are some things that you can
do to protect yourself. And one that
we didn't mention is actually the biggest
organ that they talk about is the skin.
The skin is a big organ also the lungs
we didn't mention. Yes the lungs. The
lungs help us breathe but yeah the skin is
one of the largest parts of our body.
Yeah I didn't really know that I didn't
realize that well I wasn't very good
at anatomy or biology I wasn't really
into it much but I didn't realize
that the skin is actually an organ just
like you know the heart the lungs
everything. Interesting I hadn't thought
about that. It's maybe because I feel
so comfortable and I just I get to see
it every day. Yeah and it's alive it
actually breathes you know we're changing
skin all the time so it's
very interesting so a very
medical related topic but very
interesting as well because well we didn't
touch so many other parts of the body
for example bones there are so many
names of the different bones. That's
right and you're tongue and your teeth
and your eyes all these different
pieces and parts so definitely more stuff
that we could talk about next time
but for now we hope that you've learned
something. If you have questions or
comments as always you can come to our
website englishpot.com and let us know.
All right guys we'll see you there. Bye.